Kostadis Roussos: Dragum surged forward and unleashed Tossa's caustic burr, coating both of thugs and acids. One died instantly as the corrosive Bluru melted him.
Kostadis Roussos: And the other stood soaked in acid, the session ending with a battle still raging.
Ben Pfaff: I mean, it's a pretty mean thing to do, but I did it anyway.
Ben Pfaff: They throw acid on somebody.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, actually, what you did was he barfed.
Kostadis Roussos: Strictly speaking, the mechanics of Tasha's caustic Acid Brew is you barf.
Ben Pfaff: I… need to go back and re-read the description.
Joe Beda: I didn't…
Ben Pfaff: You didn't.
Joe Beda: that, Kostadis.
Ben Pfaff: Maybe… Swap that out for another spell.
Kostadis Roussos: What is it, describe?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, there we go.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, there's a… alright, I have to find it, but there is a, there's a website that, has a, has a DnD content written by writers so that you can, like, have cool descriptions.
Kostadis Roussos: That's for sale.
Kostadis Roussos: In this era of AI work, it actually is even more valuable, because it's not… doesn't sound like it was really flawed.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. So, let me get it. So, just to… in case, Gabe, just in case you… the thing that you missed was after defeating the,
Kostadis Roussos: The, metal constructs, you talked… you guys… my wife's calling? Yeah.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Did we level up?
Ben Pfaff: Let me see, what level are we?
Daz: We did level while you were out, Gabe, I think. Oh. I'm level 9 now, are you level 9?
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Yeah, I guess Kostadis leveled for me. That's exciting.
Daz: Maybe.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, level 9.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, sorry. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Trying to figure something out. Yes, Rule 20, that's what I was looking for.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so, Gabe, sorry. You, you defeated the, you defeated the monsters. After you defeated the monsters, you discovered that the key you had was a fake.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Which… which of the keys was fake? The one…
Kostadis Roussos: The one from, the one that you guys had.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: From way back when, through the guard guy gave us?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, Callan actually gave you a fake key.
Joe Beda: There was, like, detect magic, and it didn't glow, and you're like, what up with that?
Daz: Yeah, what's going on?
Kostadis Roussos: And it turns out that's why all your magic spells weren't working, because it was just a plain old vanilla key.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And so Callan… and so when Callan, when you asked Callan, what happened, he admitted that he was using you guys as a… as a… as a distraction from where the real key was.
Kostadis Roussos: And then he told you where the real key was, and it was on Tadrick. You rushed over there, and then managed to kill him in one round, much to my irritation, forcing me to redo a large amount of the remainder of the adventure.
Daz: Oh, God.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Seems normal, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Just for the record, I was like, well,
Ben Pfaff: We do our best to screw up your plate.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, I even said, I even did my prep, I said, this is gonna be unlikely. I don't like… no rail… this is proof that I don't railroad.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, there's no railroading, even if the GM has to spend overnight rewriting everything.
Joe Beda: I'm sorry, you have helped.
Kostadis Roussos: No, you shouldn't feel sorry, dude, I got, like, dude, don't get… no, no, you don't do that. This is me…
Kostadis Roussos: bragging.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm sorry, this is me humble bragging.
Kostadis Roussos: In my other campaign, the players were kind of fed up with the adventure, and they wanted it to end, and so I have rewrote the entire ending.
Kostadis Roussos: Anyway…
Joe Beda: Did they want to start a new adventure, or they were just tired of hanging out together?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, they wanted to start a new adventure. The adventure had gone on for a little bit longer than any of us wanted.
Joe Beda: Everybody's like, we're done with this.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, no, they were kind of done with it, like, could we be done? So we ended it, and it ended in a… I actually think the ending we came up with was a lot better. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So,
Kostadis Roussos: Just to make sure you know what the… so… so yeah, so you've arrived, you're unconscious, Gabe. Why are you unconscious? Because… well, quite honestly, I couldn't figure out how to play your character.
Kostadis Roussos: That's not crazy.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Justin!
Kostadis Roussos: To be clear, the Roll20, the AI said, why didn't he do this, this, and this?
Kostadis Roussos: And I had to tell it because I was playing him and didn't know how to play them on.
Kostadis Roussos: And then it said, okay, that tracks.
Kostadis Roussos: Something along those lines. Just for the record, it, it, yes, you died because I screwed up.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Fair enough. I mean, there's a lot of tools to this character.
Ben Pfaff: It's hard to play.
Kostadis Roussos: Shadow stepped instead of using his movement speed to cross the distance, thus blowing the luminous attack.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: You know.
Kostadis Roussos: Bonus attack.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: That's fair.
Joe Beda: So are you gonna retcon things? Are we gonna fix it?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I mean…
Kostadis Roussos: He's still… just to be clear, I did the math, he still wouldn't… Ally would still wouldn't be dead.
Ben Pfaff: I have all kinds of resurrection spells.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and, and, you know, poor Glavagul's… poor Glavagul forgot to do his damage.
Kostadis Roussos: So, my point is, Glad Baguole is, is available to you.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that is Blab of the World.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And… I think the last time we did.
Ben Pfaff: So we've… we've solved everything, and I've lost.
Kostadis Roussos: No, so it's actually just the… it's the thug who's, yes, you're in the middle of combat.
Ben Pfaff: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, just so you all know, Manchun is a legendary figure.
Kostadis Roussos: That's the point you're supposed to derive from the fact that you would have heard of him.
Kostadis Roussos: He's not…
Ben Pfaff: Unrelated to our current fight.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, except for the fact that… so just because there's a bit of lore items that those of us who've been playing this game for too long know too well.
Kostadis Roussos: In Candlekeep, it's impossible to steal a book, and yet somehow somebody's been stealing books for the last 11 years.
Kostadis Roussos: That's literally.
Daz: How are they doing that?
Joe Beda: Social engineering.
Ben Pfaff: They're, they're No one keeps track of the books?
Kostadis Roussos: But,
Kostadis Roussos: Well, apparently, if you've got an avowed, who's one of the leaders of the whole thing, in your back pocket, you… and you've got the right magical artifact, anything is possible.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, it's, it reminds me of somebody who was…
Ben Pfaff: Working on a project we needed at another company, and he would sneak in commits for us occasionally, when it was important, by turning off the email notification that told people that, you know, a commit had been done.
Kostadis Roussos: Should this be recorded?
Ben Pfaff: This was… this was decades ago.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, I…
Ben Pfaff: Mr.
Daz: Statute of limitations is done.
Ben Pfaff: And, how, how, how.
Kostadis Roussos: And you just heard about this third hand, and you were not involved in it, and that's what was going on, right?
Ben Pfaff: I mean, I mean, it was over a beer in Palo Alto, and…
Kostadis Roussos: Now, you heard the story about this Cobra curve, right? You were not involved in any of it.
Ben Pfaff: Right? And you don't care, because this was… he was… this was on Citrix Zen Server.
Kostadis Roussos: Anyway, I'm gonna keep going.
Kostadis Roussos: So, yes, so, yes, and so the first rule of magical defenses is there's always a way around a magical defense.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, you have a more specific magic to get around it.
Kostadis Roussos: Exactly. So, so first of all, so Candlekeep is the property that nobody can steal books, so walking into a place and seeing a whole bunch of people stealing books is kind of mind-boggling.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? So that's one piece of work.
Ben Pfaff: My mind boggles at it.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I don't know, stealing books? Why would you steal books, right? And this is why the whole thing where, you know, getting a book from Candle Keep is a big deal.
Ben Pfaff: Have they ever considered just copying the books?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: I imagine there's some DRM on some of these books, magical DM.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, yeah, they've thought about copying these books, but it's not clear how that would produce a good paper.
Ben Pfaff: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, I'm sure there's a program dedicated to coming up with automated mechanisms of doing that, but that pre-search program didn't go anywhere.
Ben Pfaff: Well, maybe it's hard to copy magic books.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so anyway, so, so yeah, so, so, so they, they have…
Kostadis Roussos: So the first thing is they have… it's a place where all…
Kostadis Roussos: The books are… are… you can't steal books, so the first thing that's really weird is how the hell were books being stolen?
Kostadis Roussos: The second thing that's important is that
Kostadis Roussos: The place has a force field.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: And here there are bad guys inside, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Whatever mechanism somebody was using to get the books.
Daz: It could bring the bad guys in, too.
Kostadis Roussos: Brought… brought… may have brought the bad guys in, right?
Kostadis Roussos: The third thing is… and the third thing is that, the third piece of…
Kostadis Roussos: Lore… okay, and Manshoot. So Manshoot, so the… so the Zantarum are, you know, have gone through every… this is a meta-critique… the Zantarum have gone through every bad decision of the Dungeons & Dragons community over the last 30 years.
Kostadis Roussos: But…
Kostadis Roussos: They were originally founded by this guy, by this one group, and then Manchun takes over, and Manchun decides to go turn them into an evil cult of Baal. He's eventually killed, but because this is, you know, comic book villain, he can't die, so he keeps coming back in all different possible ways.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so he's a very powerful wizard who keeps showing up over and over again.
Kostadis Roussos: He's like the ultimate bad Benny.
Kostadis Roussos: And every time he shows up, it's not like, you know, a teleporter mistake where he turns into a good guy, like,
Kostadis Roussos: Are everybody's favorite Kenku?
Ben Pfaff: Where, where he, became a we're bearer, was it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, we're there, and then literally did he know that that turns him good, like…
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Who knew?
Kostadis Roussos: Who knew? Right? So yes, so…
Ben Pfaff: He certainly didn't beforehand.
Kostadis Roussos: But he had such good tutelage from Milo Goodbarrel.
Kostadis Roussos: And rationalizations.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Exactly.
Kostadis Roussos: You don't steal everything, you steal enough to cover appropriate expenses, operational overhead.
Kostadis Roussos: A reasonable, a reasonable salary!
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Supplies or whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: We got supplies.
Daz: There's, like, thieves, and then there's politicians.
Ben Pfaff: That you're…
Daz: They're the same, they just have different names.
Ben Pfaff: This makes me wonder what we can justify to our VCs after the Series A.
Daz: We'll get my little.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, my wife just texted me.
Ben Pfaff: Did I tell you guys?
Ben Pfaff: I don't know, last week, or the week before?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you got… you told us about the Series A.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, it closed, we got the money, so it's as if…
Kostadis Roussos: Excuse me.
Ben Pfaff: bank account.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, I don't know if Gabe heard that, but yes.
Daz: And you were also saying that with the revenue you have coming in and everything else, like, it sounds like this might be the last time you have to raise.
Ben Pfaff: I… I don't know how that… we don't know, but we're… we've got revenue, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, what's up?
Daz: Awesome.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, just so we're on the same page. Alright, so Daz, I'm assuming you've run over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Down the hallway.
Kostadis Roussos: If you, if you can see the Roll 20.
Daz: Yes, I can see, well, I… I had handed off the…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so the gem is in… that's why Gregam has the red dot.
Daz: Okay, that's right, that's right. Okay, cool.
Daz: I mean, I ran down there for a little bit, but I don't know, like, I don't want.
Kostadis Roussos: That's what… so could you place yourself where you think you are?
Daz: I would say, like, I… I'm around the corner, so I don't have line of sight to the… to the background here.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Should just stop with that.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you.
Ben Pfaff: I… I feel like I had some sort of clever scheme for,
Ben Pfaff: for tricking people about the keys, but I can't remember what it was now.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. So, it's the thug's turn first.
Ben Pfaff: So did we already do the acid damage on the thug for his turn?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I do not think we did that, because he only… we did, the first round. Does he take damage on his round?
Ben Pfaff: he… he takes… He takes damage at the start of each of his turns.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so roll first damage.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, let's… Roll 2, die, 4.
Ben Pfaff: 8.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he takes 8 points of damage.
Ben Pfaff: And let me see what the,
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, they, they really got… they improved the, did you see how they improved the blood spurtle?
Ben Pfaff: Oh, okay, so, he can use an action.
Daz: 22 or whatever.
Ben Pfaff: to…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I know, I mean, they… sorry, what'd you say, Ben? Sorry.
Ben Pfaff: He can use an action to scrape it off, otherwise it just keeps going.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: He figures that, if he doesn't,
Kostadis Roussos: You have… this is a concentration spell, right?
Ben Pfaff: It is, so the blessings, I guess.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so the Bless ends, but since it's a concentration spell, he's going to… What's he gonna do?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, there's Thorne over there, and there's you, and you've got the,
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, hold on, let's do a couple more things…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I don't have to do them yet.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so the thug will just whack at Gregor.
Ben Pfaff: why I was afraid of that.
Kostadis Roussos: Cause that was, like, the most, like, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: But, I mean, he's got, like, really bad attack routines, so it's not gonna be, like.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that's a miss.
Ben Pfaff: That's a mess, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You guys can see that, yep. And that is another miss. Both, hits with the mace fail, and
Kostadis Roussos: The LA Shades… Shights, shouts, shouts,
Kostadis Roussos: Don't go after him, drag him! Don't go after the cleric! Go after the wizard! The wizard's the one that we want, he's got the key!
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Ben Pfaff: Too late.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, 2, 3… so, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, both of you get an attack of opportunity against the thuck.
Joe Beda: Who's… who's both of you?
Kostadis Roussos: Gregam and Forum.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, because he ran away?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Ben Pfaff: Okay.
Joe Beda: next to me? I mean, I'll take it, don't get me wrong.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Ben Pfaff: In that case, I'll attack him with my mace.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, that's a mess, I guess.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you do 17 points of damage?
Joe Beda: No, that's if he's undead, I did 9 points of damage, goddammit.
Ben Pfaff: I assume his AC is higher than 9.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah. Just for the record, Don Bringer is a she, we've decided, canonically.
Joe Beda: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: It's gonna be hard for me to remember that, but I will do my.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just, you know, and, and yes, I know.
Joe Beda: Because my first girlfriend in high school was named Dawn.
Ben Pfaff: Well, and
Kostadis Roussos: You know, that's how I'm gonna remember it, just for the record.
Joe Beda: I'm glad you God hushed.
Kostadis Roussos: I didn't want to share. Oh, by the way, Gabe, we all fi- everybody finally learns you're married.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: You've said it, like, 15 times.
Joe Beda: I didn't know you were gay, dude, and I'm like, it's, like, nothing like a group of dudes to be like, we've been playing for God knows how long, and I'm like, who knew?
Daz: Probably weird.
Kostadis Roussos: Dude.
Joe Beda: Nope.
Daz: Like, yeah, I was…
Kostadis Roussos: I just want you to know that we… I just wanted you to know.
Joe Beda: I didn't…
Kostadis Roussos: I didn't think I was sharing anything, but apparently I was.
Joe Beda: I mean, like, whatevs, but also, who knew?
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: For what it's worth, I have no… Kostatis, you have mentioned my husband several times in these sessions, but I guess it didn't register.
Kostadis Roussos: I didn't think it was a secret, so I just said it, but yeah, so, like, apparently it finally registered.
Ben Pfaff: Isn't?
Kostadis Roussos: I just wanted you to know, Gabe, so that you're aware of it.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: I'm aware.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, you're a weird thing, I'm afraid, no, no.
Joe Beda: Remember we were married to a Jewish?
Kostadis Roussos: Like, don't register these things. That's my point. We're a true guy group. I just… that's the point. I wanted you to understand that I didn't want you… I wanted you to be part of the group, like, we don't register the important things.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: That's awesome.
Kostadis Roussos: Gregam, you missed, right?
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, isn't Dawn canonically female? I remember that from, like, the, the Iliad, like, Rosie Finger Dawn, that thing, that whole thing.
Kostadis Roussos: No idea.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, I need to do some initiative rolls, so good.
Daz: So, it's… I'm ready, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, just give me… yeah, give me a sec, give me one sec!
Daz: Second, man.
Kostadis Roussos: I know you're ready.
Daz: Figure out what that's gonna be.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I know.
Daz: When I actually go to kick his ass, so…
Kostadis Roussos: What is the solution.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. I need a D20. I have plenty of D20s.
Daz: Do I have an idea how many hit points the thug has?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's not a particularly buff dude.
Daz: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, surfing. Alright, okay. So, first things first…
Ben Pfaff: Where did it go to the thug 3 times in a row?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's… I'm just,
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just, I have to come back gets more interesting in a second. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So,
Kostadis Roussos: So, a couple things happened. One is, a Centaurum agent
Kostadis Roussos: walks past Daz and the thug.
Kostadis Roussos: And,
Ben Pfaff: I'm actually.
Joe Beda: He just, like, wanders in like trumpeted debate?
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Daz: If he walks by me, don't I get an attack of opportunity?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but he's also disengaging, so nobody can attack him.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So… he seems very… just… let me walk you through what happens. So he arrives in the room.
Kostadis Roussos: he looks around, and L.A. Avonmore suddenly is in a state of Panic.
Daz: What do they… can we infer what they're in panic about?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you are out of the room, that's why I asked where you were. So the other two, Grygum and…
Kostadis Roussos: For it.
Kostadis Roussos: And you could also try Glavagul, Gabe.
Joe Beda: What… what do we roll?
Kostadis Roussos: insight or Invest… insight or, investigation, whichever one you want.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: How do I roll for Glavable?
Kostadis Roussos: You roll a D20 and add his…
Joe Beda: Not a 6.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I mean, if you roll…
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: I know.
Ben Pfaff: And with a plus 9, I got a 12.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, hold on, let's just,
Kostadis Roussos: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… so he's freaked out. Why is he freaked out, you might ask?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, I take it back, that's not what happens.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, sorry, take it back.
Daz: Okay.
Daz: somebody is going to be upset later. I'm… I had a premonition to.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you did, you did, you did have a premonition. Alright, go for it. First initiative.
Kostadis Roussos: Daz, you're up.
Daz: Alright, so I'm up. I am gonna misty-step my ass right here, and then fireball the thug.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: He's down, roll, 8D6.
Daz: Roll A, a single D6?
Kostadis Roussos: No, 8D6, 8, as in the number 8.
Daz: For my fireball?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah! Set a fireball.
Daz: Can I just click the… the…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, I'm just, I'm sorry, I'm just, like, looking at how many hit points he has left, and I'm just going, if you don't kill him, this is gonna be epic.
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, no, you'd have to do… you'd have to roll pretty well to kill him, so roll.
Daz: It didn't work. Oh, there it goes.
Daz: That seems wrong.
Ben Pfaff: Zero.
Kostadis Roussos: what happened was you… well, whatever. How about this? Type R… slash R8D6.
Daz: I thought I'd try this and see what happens.
Daz: I'm just…
Ben Pfaff: I'm just kidding.
Daz: I'm gonna give up on that.
Kostadis Roussos: Technology failed.
Kostadis Roussos: 25. Oh! Oh, if he makes the saving throw, he survives by one hit point!
Ben Pfaff: Whoa.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… I think I have to roll a 17.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, and he rolls a 17!
Ben Pfaff: Oh!
Daz: Damn, damn, damn.
Kostadis Roussos: I think one hit point.
Kostadis Roussos: So what happens is the explosive fires rage, like, you've now, like, everybody knows that there's a big fight going on on the Hightower.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? On the walkway of the Hightower.
Ben Pfaff: Do you think the fireball was a hint?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, the fireball was… but the more important point is the fireball actually worked!
Ben Pfaff: Yeah.
Daz: Because it normally should be muted by the protection thing, so everybody's now gonna know that, basically, it's like the dream where you're in school and you're in your underwear.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Yeah, everybody is gonna realize that their… that Candle Keep is now in its underwear, and they don't have.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, right, yeah, so, like, the fact that the fireball even worked!
Ben Pfaff: Got it.
Kostadis Roussos: is con… is concerning. Never mind, and of course, you know, immediately, half the about are running in… you hear screaming, you hear panic, you hear the bell ringing.
Daz: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: And if you could, you would see people taking notes and preparing their monographs.
Kostadis Roussos: Because what do you do? What do you do in a situation like this? Why conduct the experiments you've been waiting years to?
Ben Pfaff: You take notes. Exactly.
Kostadis Roussos: You take notes. You take notes. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that's what you do. A Legos… Over here… And he kills the thug.
Kostadis Roussos: Kills the fuck.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… he pauses. Like, this is kind of like, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: You're getting the impression that this guy's an interesting character.
Kostadis Roussos: By the way, Zaltier, Global Goals Initiative, same as yours.
Kostadis Roussos: Just so that I don't… couldn't… again, too many character sheets.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: He suddenly, he stops.
Kostadis Roussos: And,
Kostadis Roussos: I'd like to stop, but not surrender, I'm aware how that sounds, and I have no reason to stop.
Ben Pfaff: Just, just, just a timeout for a moment?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, just to time out for a moment. Daz roll your investigation.
Daz: Okay.
Daz: Everything's really delayed.
Daz: I might restart my browser.
Kostadis Roussos: For some reason, it's treating all your die rolls as zeros, so you're gonna have to add the D20 to it.
Daz: Alright.
Daz: It's actually,
Kostadis Roussos: Did you, did you maybe…
Daz: I get advantage, so it's, 21.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he's… you notice that he's, like, listening towards the stairwell where you guys came up.
Kostadis Roussos: He's not looking at you, as if he's waiting, trying to see something.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, I have nothing left.
Kostadis Roussos: I have nothing left. You will have probably counted how many spells I've casted. Pauses.
Kostadis Roussos: I'd be insulted if you hadn't.
Ben Pfaff: I'm ticking him off on my fingers, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Right, right, right. But I know which two lines of the cryptogram matter, I know where the room under the keep is, and I know the name of the person in Medden Zobaransen who has been paying to keep your drow breathing.
Kostadis Roussos: I would very much like to tell all of it to somebody with a locked door.
Daz: My fireball acts as a pretty good lock on this door way.
Daz: We can have a conversation now.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Daz: Like, I don't trust anybody that's trying to delay and get us to go someplace else that they might lead us to someplace bad.
Daz: I don't know, what do you guys think?
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, so, what's your, what's your,
Ben Pfaff: And I must have some kind of a hush spell or something.
Kostadis Roussos: He's like… he looks… I mean…
Kostadis Roussos: Your investigation tells you that this guy's not a murderer.
Ben Pfaff: This is…
Kostadis Roussos: He's got whatever plan… like, you know, he's one of these people who came up with a stupid plan, and it went completely out of control, and started to fall apart.
Kostadis Roussos: And he's, like, looking for a way out.
Ben Pfaff: So he's… he's scared of people overhearing the people who would want to kill him?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that's what you're getting, yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And so, the first thing you could ask is, what does he mean by a locked door?
Ben Pfaff: Yeah,
Ben Pfaff: That is a good question. Do you mean just, behind… in a place where it's hard to hear?
Ben Pfaff: Or something more literal.
Kostadis Roussos: Pardon me?
Ben Pfaff: Do… do you… do you just…
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, I… because in about 4 minutes, people will be coming up these stairs, will be very disappointed in me, and you strike me as the more reasonable disappointment.
Ben Pfaff: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, I'm assuming at some point somebody walks over to Daz and Dissolt here and cures him, so if you want to burn a heal spell, this would be the right time.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, I, I go ahead and, how badly hurt is he?
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Good.
Kostadis Roussos: That's what you prom… Falked out.
Ben Pfaff: Zero out of how much?
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Zero, oh god, the screen hides… 57.
Kostadis Roussos: By the way, you're 9th level.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Yes, I saw that! That's exciting!
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know, I don't know, I don't know if I had to do anything.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: No, nothing interesting at that level, but thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, just wanted you to be aware.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, then I'll cast, it looks like, Healing Word.
Ben Pfaff: Did that roll? Did it roll correctly? Okay, there you go.
Ben Pfaff: And… let's see, where is he? I have to go over and actually touch him for this.
Kostadis Roussos: LA kind of moves over here. He still has the ability to cause, like, staggering amounts of damage, right? Do not forget.
Kostadis Roussos: with his cantrips.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Come on.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: It's exciting.
Kostadis Roussos: Combat starts, it starts at the top of the initiative order as before, alright?
Kostadis Roussos: So, he says, he looks at you, and he says.
Kostadis Roussos: Because in about 4 minutes, the people coming up those stairs will be very disappointed in me, and you strike me as the more reasonable disappointment. And I figured that they might be reluctant to put me in prison, but I'm sure I could convince… you would be willing to convince them, to put me in prison in Candlekeep.
Kostadis Roussos: you realize that this guy's so much attached to the idea of being in Candlekeep that he'd prefer being in prison in Candlekeep.
Ben Pfaff: Hmm.
Ben Pfaff: Do we know anything about what prison is like in Candlekeep?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you do. It's a place where spells can't be… it's like the perfect place to be if you are, if you never want somebody with a large amount of magical power to get in.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, this actually makes sense. And,
Kostadis Roussos: You know.
Ben Pfaff: this week.
Kostadis Roussos: Because remember, when you arrived, Callan Strongbranch wanted to put the, little drow in prison?
Ben Pfaff: And on the other hand, do… do…
Ben Pfaff: He's worried that the others would just want to kill him, is that it?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I mean, you know, Callan, Strong Branch, who knows who else?
Kostadis Roussos: Right? The rest of the Avowed. Like, I mean, the guy was involved in a plot that involved, like, lots of their peers dying, right?
Kostadis Roussos: he figures that you guys are not as emotionally attached to, you know… he did create a plot that resulted in the death of Janusi, the death of Bookworm.
Kostadis Roussos: The death of Silvara's son.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, he's a… he's a killer.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, he's kind of… he's created an environment of mass murder, so he's kind of like, you know, thinking if he's gonna surrender, you guys are probably the best group to surrender to.
Ben Pfaff: Safest for him, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: And he's not the I-wanna-fight-to-the-end kind of person.
Kostadis Roussos: And you also, you know, so he's sort of sitting there, he's burned through all of his spells.
Ben Pfaff: Alright, let's place him under arrest.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so is that your call? Place him under arrest?
Daz: That's true.
Ben Pfaff: And, then, then turn them over to the mercy of the, of the Council.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so…
Joe Beda: It'd be like one of those movies where the bad guy actually convinces everybody to let him go, and you just end up being pissed off and angry, and then want to just kill him anyway?
Ben Pfaff: I mean, the, the academic council, they'll, they'll,
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he'll lose his academic privileges.
Joe Beda: There's nothing worse.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm like, you know…
Ben Pfaff: Might lose his library card.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes, I mean, you know, or… well, I mean, in Candlekeep, absolutely.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? So, who, who grab, who puts, who puts him, who, who ties him up?
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: I mean, I literally have a feat for that.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, in that case…
Ben Pfaff: Better do it.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, right, you do have a feat for tying people up.
Ben Pfaff: What's that one called?
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Something about street justice, I think it is?
Ben Pfaff: Oh, really? Okay.
Ben Pfaff: It is, in fact, judicially tying people up, huh?
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Yeah, sturdy knot.
Joe Beda: Ben, I know what you're talking about, I'm not playing that game.
Kostadis Roussos: Which game?
Ben Pfaff: There's a Japanese… it's called Hojojutsu. It's the way that they used to allegedly tie people up judicially during the samurai era.
Joe Beda: That's not what he's talking about.
Joe Beda: So…
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Anyway, Kostadis, what should I roll? My feet makes it hard to escape, but I don't know what to roll for time.
Kostadis Roussos: Whatever.
Kostadis Roussos: If it makes it hard to escape, then…
Kostadis Roussos: No, he's just standing there, waiting for you guys to tie him up.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Okay, so he's tied up, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I just, I mean.
Joe Beda: The fact that you're asking makes me think that he's gonna try and escape, and it matters who actually ties him up. That's why we're actually…
Kostadis Roussos: Why would you think that?
Joe Beda: Because the statues always come alive and attack you.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And Thorin's looking around… and Daz, who's read the book carefully, is always looking at skeletons.
Daz: Yes, you gotta be… you gotta be aware and afraid of armed skeletons.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… Here's what happens next.
Kostadis Roussos: Daz.
Ben Pfaff: Did we lose…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, I'm just trying to… I'm just trying to, okay, I'm just trying to run the combat here. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay…
Kostadis Roussos: I did roll his initiative beforehand, so there can be… just for the record.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so what happens is, you're sit… you're standing over there, right?
Daz: Yes, I… yeah, I popped out there, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You popped up there. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Said assassin appears now.
Joe Beda: It's like one of those TV shows where there's all these, like.
Joe Beda: Cameos of random-ass people just showing up in the middle episode.
Daz: Yeah, yeah.
Ben Pfaff: An… an assassin? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So… an assassin, yes. He goes…
Kostadis Roussos: He's dressed in Centaurum, he looks, you know, the part, right?
Ben Pfaff: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. He goes, Alay looks at him, holding his hands out, like this.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, you know, showing that he's been captured, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Goose.
Kostadis Roussos: Took your time, but they have had me since the landing.
Kostadis Roussos: And he points his, you know, he shows his hands. It's not a loss, it's a position, I've been in the room, I know exactly who is carrying what.
Kostadis Roussos: And he points to Daz, so the assassin tries to kill Daz to grab the gem, because that's who he thinks has the gem.
Kostadis Roussos: Of course, the assassin's about to be disappointed.
Daz: Submit.
Kostadis Roussos: But…
Daz: So this one is the assassin and is now trying to kill me, is that what you said?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, because he thinks you have the gem.
Joe Beda: Oh, by the way, like, I get to attack him then, because, what is my thing?
Kostadis Roussos: He gets his first attack, then you get his life, let me just…
Ben Pfaff: He wants the gem, not the key.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he wants the gem.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, he wants… yes?
Daz: I was just gonna say, I wonder what the gem… because that's the gem where if you crush it or whatever, the thing comes to you, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so just, just, just because you have an amazing investigation.
Daz: Yes, my passive investigation's 24.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, so, so, so, in the.
Daz: I'm omnipotent.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, and…
Kostadis Roussos: In these plot moments, I will share with you what's going on, because Dad would have figured all of this out by now.
Daz: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And… but I think I'm gonna start having to spin it conspiratorially just to fit your personality.
Daz: Okay.
Daz: I'll be, I'll be like the, the dude from Always Sunny that's got the pictures and the wires.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, exactly.
Daz: Yeah, it's okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So what you figured out… okay, so just to be clear.
Kostadis Roussos: LA thinks only an idiot would bring the second key, the room where he needs the second key.
Ben Pfaff: Well, it's a good thing that, well, actually, sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, right. So he assumes that the key is somewhere in Candle Key.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And he probably thinks that whoever put it there probably didn't put it on somebody and hid it somewhere.
Kostadis Roussos: So he wants the sapphire to get the key. The reason he was gonna crush it was to get the key in his hand.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Daz: But books have been leaving, bad guys have been coming in, it's entirely possible the key's not even here.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, I mean, he… and if you… and even if you guys showed up, and Tadrick is here, right? Remember Tadrick, who…
Daz: Yeah, the cheese.
Kostadis Roussos: isn't dead. He's figuring that you guys must have run straight here and dropped the key somewhere.
Kostadis Roussos: Because, like, you're too…
Ben Pfaff: But it's too small.
Kostadis Roussos: It's hard to bring both keys into the room!
Daz: enough, but we don't have the room, because we didn't… we don't have the other key, because we haven't crushed the thing yet.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you do…
Joe Beda: I mean, like, the sapphire is as good as a key.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, you both have both keys, because Tadrick gave Grigum the real key.
Daz: But I thought we have a key and a face.
Joe Beda: The sapphire's bound, too, so we don't know where the other key is?
Kostadis Roussos: No, sorry.
Daz: I thought we had a real key, a fake key, and the sapphire.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and so the Sapphire was Ally's way to find the key.
Joe Beda: Which key?
Kostadis Roussos: The key that you…
Daz: the key that Greg… Gargan.
Kostadis Roussos: Dragon has. Yes.
Daz: Okay, so the sapphire is not the key. Basically, it's like a…
Joe Beda: Yeah, we already have.
Daz: conventional loop, it's just gonna move from his left hand to his right hand?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: I,
Kostadis Roussos: But here's the problem, right? The reason he thinks that is because he thinks you're intelligent.
Kostadis Roussos: And you would never show up in the room where both keys were required by the evil bad guy, right? You would have left the key somewhere else.
Joe Beda: Well, then somebody could grab it.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just telling you what he thought.
Ben Pfaff: I notice what he's doing, and I pull out the fake key and toss it.
Joe Beda: Really?
Ben Pfaff: saying,
Joe Beda: Did he already attack, though? Wait, just before we go…
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm just trying to explain to you the… I'm just trying to tell you what Daz figures out.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: The reason…
Joe Beda: By the way, my guardian ability means that you can't disengage with me, so I should… would have been able to attack that assassin dude.
Ben Pfaff: Right now.
Kostadis Roussos: next to Daz, he's right next to…
Joe Beda: I know, but just, like, the turn when he, like, went past me…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yeah, no, I got it, I got it.
Joe Beda: Just for the future.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, well, he didn't… he didn't have to do it this time. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: I… but… and I did not know that when I placed them there.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so he thinks that Daz has the sapphire, which is how they get the key.
Daz: Fair.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Daz: Perfect.
Daz: But don't… we don't actually have both of the real keys, right? We don't… we have a fake key.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, but Ally has one of the keys.
Kostadis Roussos: He killed Bookworm. That's how he got one of the keys.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Mozikodo kills Bookworm, gets one of the keys, gives it to Eli.
Kostadis Roussos: A lie needs.
Daz: Ally has a real key, Gergam has a real key, Gergam has a fake key, and Gergam has the… he can crush the thing, which we now think… I now think, from my omnipotence, that, it will recall the key that he already has.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And so, Eli thinks that the key… you guys have stashed the key somewhere.
Daz: Okay. Well, Gergam hasn't said anything about the key.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, that's why Ali thinks what he's thinking.
Daz: Okay, good.
Ben Pfaff: So, there's… there's two gems, each of us… Oli has one.
Kostadis Roussos: gem, only one gem.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, okay.
Joe Beda: But the gem is bound to the wrong key. The gem is bound to the key that we already have.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright? So Lay was gonna crush the gem, because he thought that would get him the second key, and then he had a whole master plan, and then Daz used telekinesis and stole the key, and now he's… now he's at…
Joe Beda: Throw the gem.
Kostadis Roussos: Told the jet.
Daz: Yeah.
Joe Beda: Good is a key.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and that's why the assassin is about to try to kill Daz, because he wants the gem.
Joe Beda: But he didn't know that the gem was actually handed off to the person who also has the key.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Joe Beda: Clear as mud.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I know, I just… I just wanted you guys to know.
Ben Pfaff: I, I have… I have the key and the gem that summons that key.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you do.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. Alright, so, he attacks.
Joe Beda: Who does he attack?
Kostadis Roussos: Daz, because he wants the damn.
Joe Beda: Okay.
Daz: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so he attacks with a… I mean, he does a lot of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. It's 20 points of damage.
Joe Beda: And immediately after this, I get to attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, dude.
Joe Beda: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, hold on, I have to roll to hit.
Daz: I have an armor class.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, I just, like, let me rule to hit, da-da-da.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so this guy, apparently, they don't know how to do this anymore.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, let's a actual short term.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, that's, okay. So, alright, so the first attacks I hit, the second attack's a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: And the third attack's a hit. So you take…
Kostadis Roussos: A lot of deck. How many hit points do you have?
Daz: Well, you said I took 20.
Joe Beda: Wait, no, no, no, I get to attack after the first attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay, go for it.
Joe Beda: I'm just saying, like, you know, we gotta, like… I may want to…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, I just… I did…
Daz: How much did the first attack hit me? Because I need to go ahead and record that.
Joe Beda: Oh, shit, I did really crappy, so don't, don't listen to that. So, what's his, armor class?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's the problem. Alright, let me just do it all over again, because this guy, I was doing it with… alright, his armor class is, 16.
Joe Beda: Yeah, no, this was a miss.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you missed. Alright.
Joe Beda: how do I recode, like, 1D0CS greater than 1CF greater than… I have no idea what that means.
Kostadis Roussos: Good.
Joe Beda: I, I'm… like, hover over the 11 that I got there. Tell me how…
Joe Beda: Like, decode that for me.
Kostadis Roussos: That does not sound… that does not look correct.
Joe Beda: I mean, I can do it again, but I'm just…
Kostadis Roussos: The dice… the de-rolling is… the de-rolling is somehow broken.
Daz: I had to… I had to shift reload.
Daz: I had the shift reload to get it to where… and then I did another thing, and it worked correctly.
Joe Beda: Alright, let me do a.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a… that is essentially saying you're old a zero.
Joe Beda: I mean, I've been having shitty rolls this session, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I know, but that's not what happened.
Joe Beda: Alright, I'm gonna roll again, cause…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that's it.
Daz: Yes, it looks like.
Kostadis Roussos: You wrote. Alright, alright.
Joe Beda: So 13 points of damage. Which probably… I just want to, like, make him a little angry.
Joe Beda: And see if he'll attack me instead.
Kostadis Roussos: No. No. He's got a job, he's got a job to do. But now that you attacked him, I now need to know… Alright, so the first attack, was a 18.
Kostadis Roussos: And the damage was… 20 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: The second attack was, total… was, 25.
Kostadis Roussos: And the damage… was 23?
Kostadis Roussos: How many hit points do you have, Daz?
Daz: I had… before all of this happened, I had 30.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so the second attack…
Kostadis Roussos: Kills you. Knocks you out.
Daz: So I'm… I'm to zero now.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you're to zero.
Daz: And do I do a death save now, or later?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you do a death save now.
Daz: And of course, the roles are not working. Why are the roles not working?
Daz: There we go.
Daz: 17.
Daz: So that's a success, right?
Daz: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that is a success. That is a success.
Daz: But I need 3 of those, and then I'm… I'm back.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you need 3 of those, or someone needs to stabilize.
Daz: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Kostadis Roussos: Let's just do this.
Kostadis Roussos: One barrel. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: There's a death saving.
Kostadis Roussos: We'll put a 1.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, that's what happens with the assassin. And then the assassin has one more attack.
Kostadis Roussos: And he uses it on…
Kostadis Roussos: That is an 18, I think that hits, right?
Ben Pfaff: I didn't hear who you said you used it.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, actually, he doesn't attack you. He attacks Allay.
Kostadis Roussos: No. Actually, he does none of the above. He looks through Daz's body and discovers, much to his horror, that the gem is not there.
Daz: There you go.
Kostadis Roussos: And then he turns to Alay. Allay now is in real panic.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, next, next person in the initiative order.
Kostadis Roussos: Daz, you're knocked out, roll a, roll a saving curb.
Daz: But, roll another one.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Wow.
Daz: So that's a failure and a loss.
Kostadis Roussos: Just one, just… just the one.
Daz: I got… I got… I have a success from the first roll, and now I have a failure. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, Thor in Europe.
Ben Pfaff: You're, you're at zero hit points?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, I'll help with that.
Joe Beda: So my first question is, I see two Glabagools, which I'm okay with.
Kostadis Roussos: No, there's only one.
Joe Beda: Okay, I mean, I'm gonna…
Kostadis Roussos: Currently, if you hit him with a slicing attack, he splits because he's an ooze.
Joe Beda: I mean, yeah, so…
Kostadis Roussos: I haven't figured out how we're gonna play that.
Joe Beda: Glove a guy.
Kostadis Roussos: Glavaguls. Is the second half sentient, or is it an unsentient?
Joe Beda: We're not going to experiment on our dear friend Glabagul.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, okay. Alright, Thorin, you're up.
Joe Beda: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Who are you attacking, just so I know.
Joe Beda: Oh, by the way, fucking A, we should have remembered. After my attack, where I actually hit him, he should have had, he should have had disadvantage on his next attack, by the way.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he gets a plus 10 to hit a 12.
Joe Beda: Alright, so he would've… he would've…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, but let me just roll, let me just roll.
Joe Beda: I'm just saying, like…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, I did not roll a 1.
Joe Beda: Okay.
Joe Beda: Alright, so…
Kostadis Roussos: That's fair, that's fair. No, I mean, you never know what could happen.
Joe Beda: 8 points of damage for on my first roll.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you're hitting him for another 8?
Joe Beda: Alright, another 14 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Joe Beda: And then, I'm gonna do… I wanna, like, juice it somehow, give me a second here.
Joe Beda: I don't like how this shit's organized, it's hard to find what's what.
Joe Beda: So he gets disadvantaged on his next attack, by the way, but,
Joe Beda: I can do…
Joe Beda: I'm gonna do Menacing Attack, which means that I do a Superiority die, which is a 1D8,
Daz: Wow.
Joe Beda: So that adds another 5, and then he has to do a… Wisdom saving throw…
Kostadis Roussos: it.
Joe Beda: Now he's frightened.
Joe Beda: Oh. Because I'm so badass.
Joe Beda: Okay, now I'm gonna use my… Action… surge…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Joe Beda: Action, surge, okay.
Joe Beda: Well, I'm gonna use…
Kostadis Roussos: more thing.
Joe Beda: That to do a third attack on him.
Joe Beda: Which is another 13 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: No, you, you, action surges all of your action, all of your… it's another multi-attack.
Joe Beda: Is it really? Fucking A, really?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so is it 15 points of damage?
Joe Beda: No, 13.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Joe Beda: And then I get to do yet another.
Joe Beda: Which is a critical hit for… God help me, I don't even know.
Kostadis Roussos: 15. Total of one… oh, you killed him!
Joe Beda: Fuckin' A!
Daz: I feel vindicated, even though.
Ben Pfaff: Wild.
Joe Beda: Like, that's what you get for taking out one of.
Kostadis Roussos: Not what I was expecting!
Joe Beda: So, wait, I just want to say, like, critical hit damage, combined.
Joe Beda: But the radi… so this is…
Joe Beda: Radiant against… I just want to make sure. So, the radiant one hand was 12,
Joe Beda: plus 6, so I think that should have been 18?
Kostadis Roussos: Are you at 18 or 23, how much damage?
Joe Beda: I'm trying to read this. Okay, so wait, so let's…
Kostadis Roussos: Total combined one… okay, so, total one-handed damage, total critical damage… wait, total one hand… okay, so… here's how…
Joe Beda: I won't you, I did 6 plus.
Kostadis Roussos: 12.
Joe Beda: So the 6 is doubled, so it ends up being 12 plus 6, which is 18.
Kostadis Roussos: So, 18 points of damage, is that how much? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: He's still… yo, he has 5 hit points, sorry about that.
Joe Beda: Okay, so he's hanging on. Wait, let me see if I can…
Joe Beda: Do anything else, give me a second here.
Joe Beda: I'm, I'm looking to see what I can do.
Kostadis Roussos: I just… I just love the visual. I'm sorry, I, I, I think…
Joe Beda: I'm just, like, pounding them.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you're, you're… I mean, this is, this is, Zaltier-level pounding.
Joe Beda: I'm gonna do…
Kostadis Roussos: I'm like… This is,
Joe Beda: I can do another 1D6 with Hill Strike.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Joe Beda: Alright, so that takes him out.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, wow, you, you, you, you knocked him out!
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. Alright, Alei is now really in a bad shape. He felt like the assassin was gonna free him, he's just betrayed you, he's got his hands dyed.
Kostadis Roussos: What do you guys want to do?
Ben Pfaff: Well, one of us is down, right? So,
Kostadis Roussos: So I'm assuming you're rushing to go healed. Alright.
Joe Beda: And I searched the body of the assassin to see if he has anything good, because, like, you know, he's, you know.
Ben Pfaff: So, what, what, what's your,
Ben Pfaff: Healing… how many… what's your hit point max?
Daz: My hint points total is… Oh, I can't see it anymore, because I gotta click this thing.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Yeah, so click into the death zone.
Daz: 56.
Ben Pfaff: 56, okay. Let's use this one.
Ben Pfaff: Is it rolling?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you're aligned.
Ben Pfaff: Why is it not rolling?
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm alive again.
Ben Pfaff: Alright, I will… oh, there we go. 40.
Daz: Period.
Daz: Thank you very much.
Ben Pfaff: And, does anybody else need any more?
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: I wouldn't mind more if…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, hold on, hold on, one, we'll do… I'm…
Ben Pfaff: How many are you short?
Kostadis Roussos: one round. This is one right, you can do one.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: so…
Kostadis Roussos: One round worth of healing, so you can…
Ben Pfaff: Okay, well, then, then I did it.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, just… just so we can keep, otherwise we're gonna…
Ben Pfaff: We do have some questions.
Kostadis Roussos: incorrect.
Ben Pfaff: Everybody wants to grab one.
Kostadis Roussos: for my head. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, now,
Kostadis Roussos: Allay is kind of, like, looking very panicked right now. Does anybody want to ask him why he's looking very panicked? I mean, the obvious reason, Daz, is that he basically surrendered, then backstabbed you, and now is back to surrendering. I mean, that's… that's the obvious read.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, I don't trust Cisco anymore.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you ever?
Joe Beda: Did we ever trust him?
Joe Beda: So the question is, are we gonna, like, be good people and offer them up to justice, or are we gonna just be like, solve the problem right here?
Ben Pfaff: Let's… I feel like the cruelest thing to do would be to turn them over to the Academic Council, so I'm in favor of that.
Joe Beda: I think, like…
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, that's… I mean, that's Greg… Graghum's, you know, brought up in a cultured environment, you know, he's… he's learned from Bahamut the importance of learning and what happens when you don't have it, so there's a certain spirituality in all that.
Daz: Hmm,
Joe Beda: Is there any sort of, like…
Joe Beda: hoist him by his own petard type of thing? Can we, like… you know how, like.
Joe Beda: when the cops really want to fuck with a criminal, they, like, take him in, and then they, like, make it clear that he was talking to the cops, so they think he's a snitch. Can we do something like that?
Ben Pfaff: Oh!
Joe Beda: release him to the Zhantarum, but make the Zhantarum think that he was a snitch or something like that, so the Zentarim take care of the problem?
Kostadis Roussos: You, you, you, yeah, so, okay, so…
Ben Pfaff: Oh, yeah.
Joe Beda: I just feel like I'm chaotic neutral, and that feels like that would be.
Kostadis Roussos: You know that, I mean, you had the
Kostadis Roussos: with Bookworm, and he deprived you of that.
Joe Beda: I wanted to…
Kostadis Roussos: You're in the whole boat.
Joe Beda: fork to hang them. I feel like this is my nature to, like, try and, like.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, I think that's a, that's a, that's a, that's a, that's a good thing to think.
Ben Pfaff: You want to play good cleric, bad cleric with them?
Joe Beda: Exactly.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Joe Beda: Can we, like, let Glabagul have his way with him? I mean, something like that.
Kostadis Roussos: Gogbugo's like, I've never eaten a vowed wizard.
Joe Beda: What does Wizard taste like?
Kostadis Roussos: He's like, hmm, do they dissolve like other people?
Joe Beda: I don't know, we should find out, Gabriel.
Kostadis Roussos: He's like, KAK THAT THING AWAY FROM ME!
Ben Pfaff: We could offer him a taste.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, no, that won't be necessary!
Joe Beda: I mean, if you cut off, like, is there, like, can you cut off, like, a wizard's fingers, and then he can't wizard anymore? I mean, like…
Ben Pfaff: I thought it was the heart.
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know, the somatic parts, I mean, but there's ways of working around that, you know, you have to relearn your motion.
Kostadis Roussos: We're no longer ableist that way in 5th edition. Fair enough.
Joe Beda: Fair enough.
Kostadis Roussos: We were, just to be clear, we were.
Ben Pfaff: A little bit of physical therapy.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, a little bit of… we have to relearn the movements, but, you know…
Kostadis Roussos: Turns out it's the movement… it's not the specific digit, it's the movement, you can do it in different ways.
Kostadis Roussos: Anyway, alright, so while you're doing that, Alei is, meanwhile, now Allay starts crying.
Joe Beda: Okay, I have no sympathy for him, fuck him.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, yeah, and he goes, you don't understand.
Joe Beda: Explain it to us.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to stay in the room while he explains it to you, or do you want to leave the room?
Ben Pfaff: Why…
Joe Beda: That feels like a very loaded question.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, it does.
Joe Beda: like, you know, roll for initiative type of question.
Kostadis Roussos: No, just, did…
Ben Pfaff: I mean, is it very…
Kostadis Roussos: My wife's calling me.
Ben Pfaff: that I… I wanna…
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: while we wait on Kostadis, were we doing something in this room? Like, why were we here to begin with?
Daz: I think we saw…
Ben Pfaff: I think we were going to go into the tower with…
Joe Beda: We were afraid they were gonna break into the tower and steal all the, like, super dangerous magic books, the… Okay.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: But we prevented that.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, okay, so… Alright, so Alley…
Kostadis Roussos: So, alright, so he's, like, freaked out now. Very freaked out.
Joe Beda: He lost.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, what… so what is… I'm going to give you a chance. What would you like to do? Do you want to stay in the… in the… in here? And… so just to remind yourself, over here at the door… there is this door over here.
Kostadis Roussos: This door apparently opens into a room, which has some kind of magical artifact.
Kostadis Roussos: That is… that can… that is used, that…
Kostadis Roussos: You've heard, is where… that controls the security of the systems.
Joe Beda: Okay, so that's the security control room.
Kostadis Roussos: That's the security control room.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: I mean, we know they've tempered with it, because the security controls are partially deactivated, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, well, but something else. Who knows with what?
Joe Beda: But they don't have both keys.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: I say we get him out of the damn room before we start asking him questions.
Daz: Yeah, especially if we've got the keys that brings in hell and damnation.
Joe Beda: Well, number one, we take the key off of him, right?
Kostadis Roussos: You now have both keys.
Daz: Yes.
Joe Beda: Yes.
Daz: Don't bring them together.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, and Gregam has one who has the other key, just want to know.
Joe Beda: So I'm the one who takes it off him, but I slip it to, Zeltir when nobody's looking.
Daz: Yeah. I think sticking in the middle of Gabriel is probably not a bad idea.
Ben Pfaff: You want to roll for a sweatyman?
Kostadis Roussos: Glabogul, I mean, as long as Glabogul… somebody tells Glabogul to not talk about it.
Daz: Yeah, yeah, I mean, he's an awesome guy.
Kostadis Roussos: You've got to give it…
Joe Beda: Both kind of…
Kostadis Roussos: Law of Silence.
Joe Beda: Is that a ghoul's other name, Claude.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so Zolt here.
Joe Beda: Ron's not very good at following directions.
Joe Beda: Great.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Zaltier also has the key. Zaltier's very proud of himself.
Ben Pfaff: Resulting, or gone?
Kostadis Roussos: We're now taking on important adventuring missions.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: You mean Gabriel?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, Glabogul, sorry, Glabogul is, like, you know…
Joe Beda: But we handed a glove, we go, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, he gained a centimeter, you know, a half a centimeter of height.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, they're saying that 2 inches taller.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Daz: Yeah, yeah. That's cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, he… he gains it.
Kostadis Roussos: A little less power. A little less pancake-y. A little less pancake-y. All right, guys, alright, and
Ben Pfaff: Oh, at 7.30.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, as you walk out of the room, you made the right choice.
Joe Beda: So, by the way, what would have happened if he had started explaining while we were in the room?
Kostadis Roussos: well, I mean…
Daz: Bad things.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I mean, the ultra-powerful wizard shows up and breaks the door.
Ben Pfaff: Oh.
Ben Pfaff: Well, I'm glad we didn't do that.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Kostis, did you say you're awake?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, we're gonna play, though. I'm gonna be…
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Certainly.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just gonna wake up very early in the morning.
Joe Beda: I appreciate your dedication.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, dude, it's more fun.
Kostadis Roussos: Plus, it's jet lag, so I… if for whatever reason, namely, I'm too drunk from the night before, I will call… I will send a text message.
Kostadis Roussos: But in that case, I might just decide, screw it, and not go to sleep, and play.
Kostadis Roussos: Are you my guy?
Joe Beda: daughter.
Ben Pfaff: We appreciate your, dedication.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, so, yes, so, so, yes, Man Shun, Man Shun, the guy who's supposed to be dead, shows up.
Kostadis Roussos: And as he shows up…
Joe Beda: HRSA building, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, he casts a fire… a wall of force, And then breaks the door.
Daz: Hmm.
Joe Beda: The magic door that the keys actually protect?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, as… and, you know, at this point, you realize, you realize the problem of the whole magical system, right?
Ben Pfaff: that…
Joe Beda: So the whole, like, struggle over the keys is mute because this is moved.
Daz: Who's kick it.
Joe Beda: Sorry, is Moo, because this dude could just show up and, like, wave.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yeah, but he would have showed up with a lot bigger power.
Kostadis Roussos: is very much weakened as a result of that. The reason… The reason he shows up…
Joe Beda: Spreadsheet involved Kostadis.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, there was.
Kostadis Roussos: There was. I mean, Manchun wasn't gonna show up, but you guys… but in the process of doing this, you managed to neutralize Alcrist.
Kostadis Roussos: Bookworm is dead.
Kostadis Roussos: Aleah's cap… You know, I didn't say it was your fault. Alei is captured, Janusi is captured, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Callan is to the wind, and Manchun's like.
Kostadis Roussos: Has to expend massive amounts of magical power to get here.
Kostadis Roussos: So he's weakened, but, you know, the whole point of the security of this place was that the Avowed were supposed to be the final line of defense, but 5 of these wizards are out.
Joe Beda: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So he's… so he's taking a desperate gamble to get it, to get it.
Joe Beda: It's so hard to find good help these days.
Kostadis Roussos: You're… you look like you're…
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: I mean, wasn't the whole point we were trying to not have that happen? Like, isn't it bad that he's now accessing, or has access to the repository of items?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that's where Allay says he doesn't.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: O?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that was the detail he didn't tell Manchun, which is why… good that you didn't kill him.
Kostadis Roussos: But Allay is going to want something in exchange for that information.
Joe Beda: Alright, same bat time, same bat channel.
Kostadis Roussos: So, yeah, so just to be clear, in the original thing, Manchun shows up with all of his goons fully powered.
Joe Beda: Alright, so we fight a diminished Manchun.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you guys manage… now, he… all of his goons can't show up, only he can show up.
Kostadis Roussos: Secondly, you manage to capture a lay who knows what Manchun is after, precisely.
Ben Pfaff: So, Manchun is, like… this is like the boss fight.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. Or… the boss fight, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: So yes, you did manage to, diminish his arrival.
Kostadis Roussos: Significantly.
Kostadis Roussos: Good. Which is why Eli is so freaked out, because Eli was, like, now realized… Eli was thinking, there's no way Manchun shows up.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, Eli realizes that if Manchun can show up in Candlekeep, Manchun can find a way to show up in a cell inside of Candlekeep.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Christmas.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, hopefully, hopefully this all makes some amount of sense.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. Yeah.
Ben Pfaff: And so we have to figure out what can we, offer LA.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes. I mean, at this point in time.
Daz: Very good.
Daz: them alive and not letting their previous boss get pissed off and kill them is probably enough.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: protecting him just long enough for the… all the wards to be placed, you know, Manchun probably burned a lot of magical artifacts to get here.
Kostadis Roussos: It was a one-time trip kind of thing.
Kostadis Roussos: All he has to do is survive long enough to not be killed. Have none of the other avowed kill him.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: There's probably a whole bunch of people who want him dead.
Daz: Yep.
Joe Beda: Which ones are the Avowed, exactly?
Kostadis Roussos: That's the name of the Candlekeep,
Daz: The candle keep people. The librarians.
Joe Beda: Two Bonsai Candlekeep, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, yes, all the… all the… it's kind of like the clergy of Candle Keeper, the event.
Joe Beda: Gotcha, gotcha.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Joe Beda: Alright, safe travels, Kostadis.
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you so much. All the best, have a good week.
Kostadis Roussos: Take care.
Joe Beda: See you later, sir.
Ben Pfaff: It's been fun.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Yes!
Kostadis Roussos: Good.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And now you know that your friends will know about your Dungeons & Dragons, your professional things, but important details, like who you're married to…
Joe Beda: After years!
Ben Pfaff: I think I still don't remember a name, but
Kostadis Roussos: I know he's from the Southeast Asia.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: He's from Malaysia, Chen is his name. Chen.
Joe Beda: Alright.
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Which is why I was in Malaysia.
Joe Beda: That makes sense.
Daz: It's like…
Gabriel Tarasuk-Levin: Connection.
Joe Beda: Alright, have a good week, guys.
Daz: Alright, we'll see ya. Alright, bye.